vandelaypremier.com 2019-02-20

# Privacy Policy - Vandelay Design

[VandelayDesign.com](https://www.vandelaydesign.com/) is a place for reading and obtaining information about design and web design principles and obtaining graphic resources and services, and we are committed to providing you with a safe online environment for such activities. By visiting and engaging with site, we may collect certain identifying information which can and will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

VandelayDesign.com reserves the right to update this policy at any time. This policy is effective from 8/6/14.

**Collection of Personal Information  
**As a visitor to our site, you can participate in many activities without providing any Personal Information.

When choosing to participate in select activities–such as signing up for our email newsletter or Premier membership–you may be asked to provide personal identifying information such as your name and/or email address. We gather this information for the use of VandelayDesign.com only, and your information will not be redistributed to any third-party companies.

As with any website, we may also gather and store non-personal information obtained through technological resources that may be transparent to the end user through the use of cookies. Please see below for more information about cookies.

**Cookies  
**A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once approved, the file is added, and the cookie analyzes web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to provide tailored information to you in an effort to enhance your user experience. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs and/or likes and dislikes by gathering information about your preferences.

VandelayDesign.com uses traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being viewed which helps us analyze data about web page traffic in an effort to improve and tailor our website it fit you, the end user’s, needs. This information is only used for statistical analysis and then it’s removed from our system.

Cookies help us provide you with a better website by allowing us to monitor the pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie does not give us access to your computer or any information about you other than the data you choose to share with us.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. Please note that many activities on our site require the use of cookies so disabling cookies may negatively impact your user experience on our site.

**What we do with the information we gather  
**We gather information about your website activity only with the intent of improving and customizing your user experience on our site. We’re committed to protecting your privacy, so we do not sell, rent or share your personal information to or with third parties in any way other than as disclosed in this Privacy Policy. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting, but you always have the option to opt-out of such messages.

**Security  
**We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure, and in an effort to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable electronic and managerial procedures to ensure the information we collect online is secure.

**Links to other websites  
**Our website may contain links to allow you to easily visit other websites of interest. Once you use these links to leave our site, please note that we do not have any control over the content or your use on that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide when visiting these other sites. Also, such sites are not governed by this privacy statement, please you should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**Controlling your personal information  
**You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time. Simply [contact us](https://www.vandelaydesign.com/contact/) and we will remove your personal information from our system.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please [contact us](https://www.vandelaydesign.com/contact/), and we will correct any information found to be incorrect as quickly as possible.

**Comment Policy**  
[Our blog](https://www.vandelaydesign.com/blog/) allows visitors the opportunity to leave a comment in response to a blog post. The purpose of the comments section is to encourage involvement and discussion among readers. All comments are moderated and we reserve the right to delete comments for any reason. Common reasons for comments not being approved include:

  * Comments that offer no real value to other reasons
  * Comments that appear to be entered by a spam bot
  * Comments that appear to be entered only to promote a link of the commenter
  * Profanity or inappropriate language
  * Insulting or hateful comments directed at other commenters or the article author

We also ask commenters to use their real name (or a pen name if preferred) when leaving a comment instead of a keyword stuffed name.

If you have any questions on this policy please [contact us](https://www.vandelaydesign.com/contact/).

**Minors  
**We do not intend to solicit or collect personal information from anyone under the age of 18 without parental consent. If you are under 18, do not enter information on this site or engage our services. If you believe a child of yours under the age of 18 has entered personal identifying information, please [contact us](https://www.vandelaydesign.com/contact/) immediately to have the data removed.
